SANDRA LOPEZ GUARDADO

PROFESSIONAL OVERVIEW

I am a highly skilled and motivated professional currently working for Perth Children's Hospital and Sandz Studio, my freelance graphic design business. I have extensive experience working on a wide variety of print and digital projects, delivering graphic design solutions for small businesses and clients. During my time at Crown Perth as a Junior Graphic Designer I worked cohesively in the marketing department creating and editing assets that met project briefs and aligned to Crown's corporate brand guidelines, mission statement and values.

I am committed to delivering outstanding outcomes in all facets of my work. I enjoy working collaboratively and building rapport with team members, clients and stakeholders. I possess strong interpersonal skills that allow me to thrive in team environments. I am committed to professional development and continuous learning and growth. I work best in diverse, inclusive environments that not only encourage resourcefulness and self-accountability, but also support a positive workplace culture.

KEY SKILLS

- Liaise with managers, stakeholders and agencies to deliver projects on time and in line with project briefs.
- Excellent time management and organisational skills with the ability to work on multiple projects concurrently.
- Deliver effective and creative design solutions working collaboratively within a creative team.
- Creating project deliverables that support brand identity and answer communication and business briefs.
- Understanding the importance of maintaining a brand voice in line with marketing strategy objectives.
- \Diamond Design assets in line with marketing and campaign objectives as well as the corporate brand style guide.
- \Diamond Progressing concepts and ideas into considered design solutions for digital and print applications.
- Produce collateral for events, campaigns and projects for internal and external stakeholders.
- Work collaboratively on small and large scale campaigns including site wide campaign roll outs.
- \Diamond Produce graphics and imagery for use across multiple channels including billboards, social media, email, web and a variety of printed comms.
- Create assets for eDM's, social media, web and screen graphics, posters, signs, vinyls, flyers and booklets. 0
- \Diamond Designing with accessibility in mind in accordance with company and government standards.
- Project administration, document management, record keeping and version control.
- \Diamond Knowledge of branding techniques and design principles with a keen eye for design application.
- Knowledge of web and print specifications, print processes and artwork specifications including formatting content for digital and print roll outs.
- \Diamond Liaise with external printers to produce campaign deliverables in a business environment.
- Produce high quality content using a quality check and proof process.
- \Diamond Establishing rapport with internal and external stakeholders to build strong and positive professional relationships.
- Present project proposals and presentations to internal and external stakeholders.

SYSTEMS AND SOFTWARE

- \Diamond Advanced skills: Indesign, Illustrator, Photoshop, After Effects, Bridge and Acrobat.
- UX/UI design software Figma and Adobe XD.
- Website design and builds using WordPress, Wix and Squarespace.
- \Diamond Knowledge of HTML + CSS.
- Social media content scheduling: Hoot Suite and Later across all social channels.
- eDM marketing using Mailchimp. \Diamond
- Microsoft Suite: Word, Power Point, Excel and OneNote.
- Task and team management tools: Trello, Notion, Slack and Microsoft Teams and Xero. \Diamond
- 3D and 2D modelling software: Sketchup, ArchiCAD, AutoCAD and Twinmotion.

EDUCATION AND QUALIFICATIONS

Basics of Web Development Certificate She Codes - HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, Python, Django. **TBC 2024**

Diploma of Graphic Design North Metropolitan TAFE	2021

EXPERIENCE

Design and Marketing Internship

2023

Fifth Avenue Consultancy

North Metropolitan TAFE

- Assisting with and attend promotional events, presentations and functions.
- Assist with client solutions, building proposals, audience insights and promotional material.
- ♦ Create graphics for campaigns, events and clients.

Campaign and Marketing Internship

2023

Digital Loop

- Update marketing strategy including social media posting schedule.
- Create content, including copy, graphics, reels, and other visuals to post across social channels.
- Updating website, remarketing, building eDM campaigns, and other marketing material and signage.
- Assisting with and attend promotional events, presentations and functions.
- Assist with client solutions, building proposals, audience insights and promotional material.
- Preparing campaign reports and screens for clients to provide key Performance Indicator.

PADC Skulls Awards Volunteer

2022 - 2023

Perth Advertising and Design Club

ACHIEVEMENTS

Perth Advertising and Design Club Student Skulls Award

2021

Digital Design UX/UI – 'The Self Check Out' A Breast Cancer Awareness Campaign

A behaviour changing campaign by Sandra Lopez and Chloe Mitchell that influenced the public to perform breast checks at random times during the month in line with new public health messaging. This campaign utilised established shopping habits as the first point of interaction, partnering with instore and online retailers to influence shoppers to perform a breast check when trying on clothes in change rooms or at home.

Propel Youth Arts - Drug Aware Yculture Metro Grant Recipient

2021

Artist Exhibition - Press Flex Relax: Presented By Drug Aware

This project that brought together 9 emerging local Boorloo based artists and writers to collectively respond to the theme of grounding. The exhibition showcased each artists final project and their unique take on the theme. The exhibition completed works where documented in a zine created by Sandra Lopez & Ailsa Waddell.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Sandz Studio 2020 – Present

Freelance Graphic Designer

- Manage multiple client briefs clients correspondence, invoicing and file management.
- Develop rapport with clients to better understand their project needs.
- ♦ Create innovative design solutions and high level copy writing for website, social media and publications.
- ♦ Liaise with clients to develop logo, brand and product outcomes that the client is highly satisfied with.
- Deliver project requirements on time and to a high standard.
- ♦ Understand the responsibility I assume when committing to deliver a project outcome for a client.

2018 - Present

Ward Clerk | Burns unit

- ♦ Provide training and onboarding for new Burns Unit clerical staff.
- ♦ Create workflow documents and clinic structure resources for clerical processes.
- Provide clerical and reception duties for the Burns Unit with a focus on customer service.
- Administration and office management including ordering supplies, stationery and documents.
- Data input and processing to a high level of accuracy.
- ♦ Processing admissions, discharges, referrals, appointments and medical record maintenance/filling.

Crown Perth 2021 – 2022

Junior Graphic Designer

- Liaise with the marketing and PR teams to understand marketing briefs and desired project outcomes.
- Manage multiple projects starting new briefs while making edits on ongoing projects.
- Deliver project outcomes to industry, company and personal standards.
- Create content for internal and external comms as well overarching campaigns.
- ♦ Work collaboratively with other team members to deliver larger scale campaign roll outs.
- Liaise with external print companies to produce high quality signs, posters, vinyls, flyers and booklets.
- ♦ Ensure all content aligns to the Crown values and integrity plan.
- Create content that adheres to corporate brand guidelines and marketing strategies.
- Use crown project management programs to keep track of project progress, stage approvals and proof edits.
- Employ industry standard design practices including document setup, project specification requirements and file saving conventions.

Paper Mountain 2019 – 2021

Media and Marketing Officer

- Create a marketing and social media engagement plan.
- ♦ Campaign rollout using Mailchimp and social media platforms.
- ♦ Liaising with artists and the gallery manager to create social media posts.
- ♦ Creating event and exhibition collateral for print and digital channels.
- Write thoughtful and high-level copy for newsletter, social media and print gallery material.
- Work collaboratively with managers to organise and execute artist gallery events, workshops and exhibitions.
- Use KPI's to track marketing strategies and make changes to strategies where appropriate.
- ♦ Ensure exhibition collateral is reflective of the artist it represents.
- Ensure all collateral produces is reflective of Paper Mountain's values and principles.

Sir Charles Gairdner Hospital

2016 - 2019

Ward Clerk | Haematology & Oncology

Landsdale Autocare 2014 – 2015

Administration Assistant

LANGUAGES

- Spanish (Bilingual Proficiency)
- English (Native Proficiency)

REFEREES

Usnie Shakir

A/Inpatient Coordinator - Perth Children's Hospital

M: 64565692

E: Usnie.Shakir@health.wa.gov.au

Kirstin Lopdell

Senior Designer - Crown Perth

T: 0405 204 331

E: Kirstin.Lopdell@crownresorts.com.au